<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Model Human Processor</title><link>https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/</link><description>Personal site of a robot trying to pass as human, tech, culture, news, whatever catches my interest.</description><atom:link href="https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2021 &lt;a href="mailto:modelhumanprocessor@protonmail.com"&gt;Model Human Processor&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 May 2021 15:51:24 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Saturday Night Live</title><link>https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/posts/saturday-night-live/</link><dc:creator>Model Human Processor</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;Seeing news about SNL and Elon Musk online has been kind of weird. I haven't even thought about SNL since the early 90s when I only watched it rarely since my friends and I were more into In Living Color. So it has been strange seeing people talk about a show that I've largely considered dead or irrelevant for some time now. Which got me thinking about if that's just my own bias, which it largely is, or if there's something more to it. To try and puzzle that out I pulled up a cast/write list for SNL on wikipedia to see which names I could recognize. Going back to when the show first started in the mid-late 70s I see some very well known names, Chevy Chase, Dan Aykroyd, John Belushi, Bill Murray, although I know all of those from films, going into the 80s I see Gilbert Gottfried, Eddie Murphy, Julia Louis-Dreyfus, Billy Crystal, Martin Short, Damon Wayans, Jon Lovitz, Dana Carvey. Getting into the 90s I see Ben Stiller, Chris Rock, Rob Schneider, Chris Farley, David Spade, Adam Sandler, Sarah Silverman, Norm Macdonald, Will Ferrell. Coming into the early 2000s I can recognize: Tracy Morgan, Jimmy Fallon, Tina Fey, Amy Poehler, and 2010s I only notice Bill Hader, all the names after that I don't know at all. So it feels like  SNL has really gone downhill in the last 10 years or so. Maybe I'm wrong and the current cast are great, but they've done nothing to penetrate the media filters and algorithms that would make me notice them and I've only seeing the names for the first time due to SNL getting Musk to be the guest and doing a tiny bit of research. Although the viewership looks down from the 80s and 90s it's up from the lull around 2006 where it dropped under 7 million, and has been over 8 million or a bit under since so it does still seem to be doing well enough for itself. I suppose it's not as irrelevant as I thought.&lt;/p&gt;</description><guid>https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/posts/saturday-night-live/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 14 May 2021 02:14:06 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Sorcerer King and Barbarian Queen vol 2</title><link>https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/posts/sorcerer-king-and-barbarian-queen-vol-2/</link><dc:creator>Model Human Processor</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;The adventure of our unreliable narrator continues. Having arrived in town our amnesiatic hero wastes no time in getting into some kind of new trouble. The protagonists inner monologue and his actions are frequently in conflict and this is a major source of humor for the this series.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>light novel</category><category>review</category><guid>https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/posts/sorcerer-king-and-barbarian-queen-vol-2/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2021 15:25:57 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Sorcerer King of Destruction and the Golem of the Barbarian Queen</title><link>https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/posts/the-sorcerer-king-of-destruction-and-the-golem-of-the-barbarian-queen/</link><dc:creator>Model Human Processor</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;Well with the general premise right in the title what more is there to say? Another isekai although given the character gets much of his memory erased and knowledge from his life makes basically zero impact on the events in this volume, it seems like the isekai setting is mostly just a convienent starting point for the story and lore rather than adhering more closely to the standard tropes. Which is a welcome change of pace, the main character has some idiosincraticies that perhaps didn't translate well or are a type of cultural meme that I'm just missing.
The story itself is an amusing read. Our hapless main character narrowly avoids his fate, and ends up creating a golem to be his partner. It's clear that his golem is a bit special and that gets hinted at throughout.
This first volume covers the main characters arrival, setting out from the starting location, some trials, and finally arriving in civilization.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>light novel</category><category>review</category><guid>https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/posts/the-sorcerer-king-of-destruction-and-the-golem-of-the-barbarian-queen/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 17 Apr 2021 04:38:12 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Trapped in a Dating Sim: The world of otome games is tough for mobs</title><link>https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/posts/trapped-in-a-dating-sim-the-world-of-otome-games-is-tough-for-mobs/</link><dc:creator>Model Human Processor</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;The general premise is right there in the title. Our protagonist reincarnates into the world of game his sister had blackmailed him to play for her. Which is a reasonable explanation to have someone who would not be the target audience of such a game play through it. The description of the game from the prologue also allows the world to be nonsensical and inconsistent in various places due to it being based on a silly game and thus still fit the story.
The one part that doesn't really fit for me is the protagonists insistance on following through with the 'logic' of the otome game world when it comes to his position and what's expected of him with finding a marriage partner. He's perfectly willing and even hoping to throw away his title to avoid having to marry some harpy, but when that fails he goes right back into the mindset of having to find a wife. There is an explanation given, but considering Leon's ownership of Luxion he hardly has any reason to be concerned. Aside from that it's a rather enjoyable story overall. Leon just can't stay out of trouble.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>book review</category><category>light novel</category><guid>https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/posts/trapped-in-a-dating-sim-the-world-of-otome-games-is-tough-for-mobs/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2021 04:55:30 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Nikola Themes</title><link>https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/posts/nikola-themes/</link><dc:creator>Model Human Processor</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;Well I attempted to update the theme of this site to one of the available options. I was looking for one with a default dark or night mode since the white is hard on my eyes. Nikola makes this fairly easy, run the command to download the desired theme, alter one or two lines in the conf.py file and it's done. Except github gave me an error on trying to rebuild the page and to try again later. So Ill have to see if it was just a hiccup in their system or if it just doesn't like this particular theme. If it continues to cause problems I'll have to look at using the custom css option or forking a theme to modify.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>blog</category><guid>https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/posts/nikola-themes/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 10 Apr 2021 05:32:28 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>In Another World With My Smartphone(LN)</title><link>https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/posts/in-another-world-with-my-smartphoneln/</link><dc:creator>Model Human Processor</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;A fairly trope laden isekai LN. Protagonist is overpowered from the start? Check, can use all magic? check, early harem setup? check, harem includes royalty? check, picks a katana as weapon? check. There's no real surprises here folks.
The smartphone gimmick from the title is a handy McGuffin item. Allowing the protagonist to referrence the internet to look up things he doesn't know how to do, exploit it's mapping feature in conjunction with magic, look up new recipes to introduce new food items, all the standard things you often get when a protagonist is some kind of isekai prepper but instead is just a regular guy but still has access to google thanks to the smartphone cheat.
I can't remember exactly what volume they get foreshadowed around 3~4 iirc, but volume 6 introduces mechas. So if you miss the earlier foreshadowing like I did and end up invested in the story having this addition really throws a wrench in the more traditional fantasy setting I prefer and goes full mech otaku. A feature that will be present in one form or another in pretty much every subsequent volume that I've read (currently have read up to and including volume 12). I've honestly debated dropping this series but tend to fall for the sunk cost fallacy and feeling that I've come this far, I might as well just keep going. It's still a fun story if you enjoy isekai series.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>isekai</category><category>light novel</category><category>review</category><guid>https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/posts/in-another-world-with-my-smartphoneln/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 02 Apr 2021 17:02:51 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Kuma Kuma Kuma Bear</title><link>https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/posts/kuma-kuma-kuma-bear/</link><dc:creator>Model Human Processor</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cute girls doing cute things the isekai? When self proclaimed hermit Yuna opens a special event box in her VRMMORPG she ends up transported to a fantasy world with her event reward (a set of bear themed equipment) and a ton of money. The main hook of her equipment being the source of abilities meaning she can never get rid of it is still a source of amusement for me even after 5 volumes, the joke hasn't gotten old yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The various arcs are more or less what one might expect from a fantasy world isekai, adventurer and merchant guilds, nobles, fighting monsters, food, etc. the fact that the protagonist is a girl in a bear onesie gives it all a fresh coat of paint and helps keep the tone fairly light hearted.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>light novel</category><category>review</category><guid>https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/posts/kuma-kuma-kuma-bear/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 17:21:50 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>That's it for game reviews</title><link>https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/posts/thats-it-for-game-reviews/</link><dc:creator>Model Human Processor</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;That's it for the games I've played in the last while. So no more reviews, unless I feel like reminiscing about some game or another I haven't played in years. I've got some backlogged book reviews I'll post next and then I'll probably be looking at Nikola themes and customizing to change  the appearance of this site.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>blog</category><guid>https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/posts/thats-it-for-game-reviews/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2021 01:24:31 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Honkai Impact 3rd</title><link>https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/posts/honkai-impact-3rd/</link><dc:creator>Model Human Processor</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;Another mobile game from the same studio as Genshin Impact. After starting Genshin I was curious about Mihoyo's other game. So I tried this out, it's another gacha waifu collector. The battle system is quite similar to Genshin's with swapping characters to use abilites, a type system, some enemies having shields, etc. Although most parts of the game were localized there were some that were not, leading the already confusing story to be even more confusing. The gameplay was pretty fun, but the confusing story eventually lost me completely and my interest in continuing waned. There were some good events during the time I did play though and the game was quite enjoyable. So it might be something I pick up again at some point.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>pc</category><category>review</category><category>video game</category><guid>https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/posts/honkai-impact-3rd/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2021 01:19:15 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Lost in Blue(DS)</title><link>https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/posts/lost-in-blueds/</link><dc:creator>Model Human Processor</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;An island survival game that truly simulates the tedious drudgery of surviving on a deserted island after a shipwreck. You get to look after your fellow survivor and try to keep them alive by gathering enough food and water each day, and leading them around the island from time to time when you need their help to move a log or solve a puzzle that allows for deeper exploration of the island. Each day is the same, fetch water, gather food, explore and gather materials. It's like looking after a pair of tomogachi. Even though there's a map, there's no feature to make annotations of what supplies appear where so you can check back for when they respawn, and the overall movement speed just feels so slow after awhile and there's no setting to increase it. Eventually I gave up, the grind was just too much and unlike other grindy games where you always felt like you were making some progress, it was possible to make no progress while playing due to bad luck with food collection, or wasting time looking for some item that hadn't respawned, etc. The pacing just felt too slow and frustrating for me, which is too bad, because my initial impressions when starting the game were quite good and it felt like a novel game experience. I'm not sure if later titles in this series address any of my complaints or not, I hope they do.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>DS</category><category>review</category><category>video game</category><guid>https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/posts/lost-in-blueds/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2021 01:10:07 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>