<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Model Human Processor</title><link>https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/</link><description>Personal site of a robot trying to pass as human, tech, culture, news, whatever catches my interest.</description><atom:link href="https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2021 &lt;a href="mailto:modelhumanprocessor@protonmail.com"&gt;Model Human Processor&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2021 01:27:22 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>That's it for game reviews</title><link>https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/posts/thats-it-for-game-reviews/</link><dc:creator>Model Human Processor</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;That's it for the games I've played in the last while. So no more reviews, unless I feel like reminiscing about some game or another I haven't played in years. I've got some backlogged book reviews I'll post next and then I'll probably be looking at Nikola themes and customizing to change  the appearance of this site.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>blog</category><guid>https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/posts/thats-it-for-game-reviews/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2021 01:24:31 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Honkai Impact 3rd</title><link>https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/posts/honkai-impact-3rd/</link><dc:creator>Model Human Processor</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;Another mobile game from the same studio as Genshin Impact. After starting Genshin I was curious about Mihoyo's other game. So I tried this out, it's another gacha waifu collector. The battle system is quite similar to Genshin's with swapping characters to use abilites, a type system, some enemies having shields, etc. Although most parts of the game were localized there were some that were not, leading the already confusing story to be even more confusing. The gameplay was pretty fun, but the confusing story eventually lost me completely and my interest in continuing waned. There were some good events during the time I did play though and the game was quite enjoyable. So it might be something I pick up again at some point.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>pc</category><category>review</category><category>video game</category><guid>https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/posts/honkai-impact-3rd/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2021 01:19:15 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Lost in Blue(DS)</title><link>https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/posts/lost-in-blueds/</link><dc:creator>Model Human Processor</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;An island survival game that truly simulates the tedious drudgery of surviving on a deserted island after a shipwreck. You get to look after your fellow survivor and try to keep them alive by gathering enough food and water each day, and leading them around the island from time to time when you need their help to move a log or solve a puzzle that allows for deeper exploration of the island. Each day is the same, fetch water, gather food, explore and gather materials. It's like looking after a pair of tomogachi. Even though there's a map, there's no feature to make annotations of what supplies appear where so you can check back for when they respawn, and the overall movement speed just feels so slow after awhile and there's no setting to increase it. Eventually I gave up, the grind was just too much and unlike other grindy games where you always felt like you were making some progress, it was possible to make no progress while playing due to bad luck with food collection, or wasting time looking for some item that hadn't respawned, etc. The pacing just felt too slow and frustrating for me, which is too bad, because my initial impressions when starting the game were quite good and it felt like a novel game experience. I'm not sure if later titles in this series address any of my complaints or not, I hope they do.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>DS</category><category>review</category><category>video game</category><guid>https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/posts/lost-in-blueds/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2021 01:10:07 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Blade and Soul(Astromancer patch?)</title><link>https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/posts/blade-and-soulastromancer-patch/</link><dc:creator>Model Human Processor</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;I made a brief return to Blade and Soul after seeing that some new classes had been released and the story had progressed a bit since my last time playing this over a year prior. So I reinstalled to see what's changed. And the answer was, not much. The main quest rewards to catch a new player/character up to speed to begin the dungeon grind have been increased a bit, but at the same time, so much content in the game is being made redundant and retired. And it's not being retired well, much of it is sloppy, it was confusing as a returning player and I feel it would also be confusing for any new player. Which all added up to the feeling that the game was running on the fumes of whatever dedicated fanbase remained.
After catching up on the story and trying out the new classes I quit again. The story is pretty grim and dark as far as MMORPGs go. And I just can't be bothered to learn the dungeon or raid encounters with my reduced level of interest in playing this game long term. Many of the features that originally got me to try this game have been stripped away or streamlined. Which is good in some ways, they were complex and grindy, but a shame in others.
Maybe I'll see where this game is at in another few years if it's still around.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>mmorpg</category><category>pc</category><category>review</category><category>video game</category><guid>https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/posts/blade-and-soulastromancer-patch/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2021 01:02:32 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Genshin Impact</title><link>https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/posts/genshin-impact/</link><dc:creator>Model Human Processor</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;I was purely f2p during my time playing Genshin Impact. When I first started seeing comments about this crop up on social media one of the descriptions I came across was "Breath of the Waifu/Husbando" for it's open world gameplay and combat combined with a gacha system for monetization. So I tried it out for longer than I was intending to, completeing all the current story content and doing the daily grind of farming primogems to pull for characters. The open world is fun to explore, hunting for chests and solving the odd puzzle.
The game suffers from the same problem as others within the gacha/mobile genre, stamina limits, grinding, rather predetory monetization with paid stamina refreshes. That being said I never felt overly pressured to spend money, the natural resin(stamina) refresh was enough to do a few events each day, and the game gave out a reasonable about of resin potions that I saved up until hitting the appropriate rank to utilize them effectively.
The team building is pretty flexible although as always a lot of min maxing takes place to build up some kind of meta, and although conforming to the meta might help clear some of the hardest content sooner and with easier to acquire equipment, you can stray from the meta and still clear most of the content the game has to offer.
Once the story is cleared and the higher ranks are hit, the bulk of the game turns into grinding for artifacts/equipment. This is heavily RNG based and a massive source of frustration for many players especially if you're attempting to clear the harder challenge dungeon with a sub-optimal team comp, or even an optimal team comp if your gear RNG has been terrible.
After playing a few months I've had my fill, I'll likely check back in from time to time as new patches hit to keep up with the story and try some of the events. The tower defense mini game in the previous event was pretty fun. But the endless rng gear grind just really kills my motivation to play daily any more.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>pc</category><category>review</category><category>video game</category><guid>https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/posts/genshin-impact/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2021 00:47:42 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Legend of Zelda: Phantom Houseglass(DS)</title><link>https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/posts/the-legend-of-zelda-phantom-houseglassds/</link><dc:creator>Model Human Processor</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;Another entry in the Zelda franchise, this one makes extensive use of the stylus for its controls, which was weird and awkward at first, and in a few areas having the stylus block part of the screen made one or two bosses more of hassle than more traditional controls would have made them. After getting used to the controls the game plays smoothly enough with some practice. Controls aside this is a solid Zelda game with everything I've come to expect from this series. It did feel a bit on the easier side though as far as bosses went, and I attribute that to the stylus controls, not that they made it easier, but the designers had to tone down the fights due to the somewhat janky and slower nature of using the stylus compared to a dpad and buttons.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>DS</category><category>review</category><category>video games</category><guid>https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/posts/the-legend-of-zelda-phantom-houseglassds/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2021 00:42:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Rune Factory: A Fantasy Harvest Moon(DS)</title><link>https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/posts/rune-factory-a-fantasy-harvest-moonds/</link><dc:creator>Model Human Processor</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;Doing chores the game? This is actually the first harvest moon related game I've ever played. I found it to be pretty relaxing, but the repeatition does wear on after awhile. The early game was largely concerned with earning money and gathering materials for house improvements, with forays into the dungeon with whatever stamina remained after my garden was tended to. After upgrading the house and unlocking the crafting stations things really picked up and there were a lot more options of what to focus on, and I really found it a shame that crafting was not available in some form earlier on. Like maybe you could borrow a crafting station in the town with a limited selection of the recipes with the skill capped at a reasonable level. The final two dungeons holding materials for the really restricts crafting progression as well. The other awkward part of the game was having a dungeon that was only unlocked during winter, I was lucky enough to progress to that point before winter hit, actually a lot before. This meant I had to spend over two weeks of game time without being able to make any meaningful progress story wise and was relegated to gathering materials, and fighting monsters. This additional time to grind meant the next dungeons became rather easy. Winter itself posed another problem in that your field is unusable, so only the plots inside dungeons may be farmed at that time.
The combat was pretty basic and not at all complicated, but was enough to do the job and had a satisfying enough feel to it. There were quite a lot of activities to do, but many of them were fairly optional unless you were planning to court a specific girl that relied on those activities to raise her affection. Overall an enjoyable experience.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>DS</category><category>review</category><category>video game</category><guid>https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/posts/rune-factory-a-fantasy-harvest-moonds/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2021 00:29:25 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Children of Mana(DS)</title><link>https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/posts/children-of-manads/</link><dc:creator>Model Human Processor</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;A fairly solid game from the mana series for the Nintendo DS. Typical hack and slash action-adventure game. I found the magic mechanic a bit clumsy due to the activation time, as well as the weapon special attack activation time feeling too slow. The other issue is being on the DS itself, the small screen is unsatisfying for the size of the stages and how many monsters can be on the screen at once. Progression wise the difficulty curve is fairly flat, with stages getting longer as the game goes on being the only change. Any trouble in progression can be solved with some additonal grinding on an easier level and gear upgrading. The game was short enough that by the time I was getting bored of the gameplay it was over, although I passed on doing a number of the optional side dungeons for each of the magic spirits, so there was still plenty more content if I had felt like continuing. The story was decent, and was in line with the feel of other mana titles. The gem grid system was interesting, and allows for some interesting specialization of specific weapons or magic if so desired, so customizing into a preferred style is possible with some effort.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>DS</category><category>review</category><category>video game</category><guid>https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/posts/children-of-manads/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 27 Mar 2021 23:47:26 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Final Fantasy IV(DS)</title><link>https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/posts/final-fantasy-ivds/</link><dc:creator>Model Human Processor</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;a 3D remake of the classic SNES title with the original(JP) higher difficulty mitigated somewhat by the augment system that grant extra abilities. The augment system is interesting, but taking full advantage of it almost necessitates the use of a guide that details how each augment is obtained. The game contains some cutscenes with voice acting, which is a nice touch. I've started this game multiple times on different consoles, and playing this version was quite the change with the difficulty increase. Bosses I remembered just steamrolling with autoattacks required actual strategy to beat which gave the game a suitable level of challenge and kept each boss interesting. The new game+ feature is there, which combined with the augments allows the game to be cleared pretty quickly and gives some replay value, but if you're trying to min max a guide is required. I didn't bother due to missing some augments as well as missing 0.1% of the map somewhere that I didn't feel like hunting across the entire game to find. I may end up playing the PSP version at some point in order to play the 'After Story' FF4.5 game that is included with that version.
The combat is classic FF action combat. Each character has a fixed job and roll within the party and gets their own time to shine throughout the story that really does a good job of fleshing out each character.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>DS</category><category>review</category><category>video game</category><guid>https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/posts/final-fantasy-ivds/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 27 Mar 2021 21:33:09 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Castlevania: Portrait of Ruin</title><link>https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/posts/castlevania-portrait-of-ruin/</link><dc:creator>Model Human Processor</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;Another solid metroid vania symphony of the night style game. There's some new systems in places with mini quests, sub weapon skill system, but the quest system has a flaw where it's possible to sell a few of the items required for a quest by mistake and have no way to get them again to finish the quest. Which happened to me and was very frustrating as I was working on completeing as much of the content as possible but didn't want to have to restart. The partner switching feature was interesting, and needed for a few puzzles, but could also be a little clunky at times. Having to equip spells make switching cumbersome so a lot of them will go to waste, the same with the large number of sub weapons available. There's probably some appeal to them for people who really want 100% clear and maxed out and that will extend the total play time, but for a casual playthrough, they're wasted or gimmicky. There's some extra modes typical of castlevania, although they're fairly short, add some replayability, but I'd had enough after finishing the primary story.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>DS</category><category>review</category><category>video game</category><guid>https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/posts/castlevania-portrait-of-ruin/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 27 Mar 2021 21:15:31 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>