<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Model Human Processor (Posts about blog)</title><link>https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/categories/cat_blog.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2021 &lt;a href="mailto:modelhumanprocessor@protonmail.com"&gt;Model Human Processor&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Apr 2021 05:36:20 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Nikola Themes</title><link>https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/posts/nikola-themes/</link><dc:creator>Model Human Processor</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;Well I attempted to update the theme of this site to one of the available options. I was looking for one with a default dark or night mode since the white is hard on my eyes. Nikola makes this fairly easy, run the command to download the desired theme, alter one or two lines in the conf.py file and it's done. Except github gave me an error on trying to rebuild the page and to try again later. So Ill have to see if it was just a hiccup in their system or if it just doesn't like this particular theme. If it continues to cause problems I'll have to look at using the custom css option or forking a theme to modify.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>blog</category><guid>https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/posts/nikola-themes/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 10 Apr 2021 05:32:28 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>That's it for game reviews</title><link>https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/posts/thats-it-for-game-reviews/</link><dc:creator>Model Human Processor</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;That's it for the games I've played in the last while. So no more reviews, unless I feel like reminiscing about some game or another I haven't played in years. I've got some backlogged book reviews I'll post next and then I'll probably be looking at Nikola themes and customizing to change  the appearance of this site.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>blog</category><guid>https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/posts/thats-it-for-game-reviews/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2021 01:24:31 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Confusing github's custom domain feature, with my dns's redirect</title><link>https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/posts/confusing-githubs-custom-domain-feature-with-my-dnss-redirect/</link><dc:creator>Model Human Processor</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;So github has this handy setting for github pages that will redirct your repo's or user's github.io page to some other server. But my dumb ass misread that and thought it was a setting to point my custom hostname at the github page and like, it needed to know what url was going to be redirecting to it for permissions or some such. But no it was a CNAME redirect.. meaning that when I went to my domain registar and pointed my custom domain at the github.io url I created a loop.I need to find some good books on that stuff at some point.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>blog</category><guid>https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/posts/confusing-githubs-custom-domain-feature-with-my-dnss-redirect/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 06:01:03 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Finding a web host</title><link>https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/posts/finding-a-web-host/</link><dc:creator>Model Human Processor</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;As alluded to in a previous post using a static site opens up some options for hosting such as github(or lab) pages. Which is what I'll be using. I'm not sure if that's in violation of their ToS, it doesn't seem to be. If a problem ever comes up I'll let future me deal with it. Luckily Nikola has support for using git pages built in so getting this to work hopefully won't be too painful.
Eventually I think it would be interesting to self host, but that's for another day.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>blog</category><guid>https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/posts/finding-a-web-host/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 15:36:08 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Picking a blogging platform</title><link>https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/posts/picking-a-blogging-platform/</link><dc:creator>Model Human Processor</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Why I am not just using WordPress or one of the other more common blogging solutions? Cost certainly isn't a factor, most or all of them have free options available. Even being open source isn't a factor since WordPress is open source. I've opted for a SSG and Nikola in particular for a few reasons.
1. to be a tiny bit contrarian
2. an SSG is a bit of an easier tool for me to wrap my head around what it's doing, especially with Nikola being written in Python, which I already am familiar with when compared to WordPress which is written in PHP and has way more features that at this time I do not feel the need to deal with.
3. The appeal of a pure static HTML site over something that needs a database, which opens up some additional free hosting options.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even if I change my mind later migrating from an SSG into some other platform should be relativeily straightforward, all the posts are just .rst files after all. (Hopefully those won't be infamous last words)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>blog</category><guid>https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/posts/picking-a-blogging-platform/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 18:13:03 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Why am I starting a blog in 2021?</title><link>https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/posts/why-am-i-starting-a-blog-in-2021/</link><dc:creator>Model Human Processor</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;Although it is amusing to entertain delusions of granduer that this site will somehow allow me to not have a day job and get invited too all of my favorite podcasts, that really isn't why I am making an attempt at establishing an online presence. Rather I wanted to create a place where I could dump my thoughts, ramblings, hobbies, and document learning about various technologies web related or otherwise. This is just a project I picked that would be the vehicle that will hopefully help me learn all these things. If I ever do figure out how monetization works, I'd be pretty satisfied if it covers the domain name registration and hosting costs.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>blog</category><guid>https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/posts/why-am-i-starting-a-blog-in-2021/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 17:51:19 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>