<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Model Human Processor (Posts about gamereview)</title><link>https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/categories/cat_gamereview.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2021 &lt;a href="mailto:modelhumanprocessor@protonmail.com"&gt;Model Human Processor&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Mar 2021 04:00:43 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Final Fantasy Origins(FF1 &amp; FF2)</title><link>https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/posts/final-fantasy-originsff1-ff2/</link><dc:creator>Model Human Processor</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;A Gameboy Advance remake of the classic NES game and another NES game that wasn't originally released outside Japan. This was also released on the Playstation. Although there are differences between each console version. The GBA version is rather easier than the original and has some optional dungeons for FF1. FF1 was probably my introduction to the whole genre, and there's way too much nostalgia that bias' my views on the game itself.
As for FF2, this was the first time playing it. There is an interesting story system with the use of keywords to progress certain story events and the playable cast is named, with temporary members coming and going throughout the course of the story which gives the game a lot more depth than the first game. The combat system is similar in how battles take place, but the leveling system is completely different. And although the leveling system is interesting in principle, where various stats and skills go up with use instead of via a more traditional experience point value, it lends itself to meta gaming and power leveling performing very unnatural things in order to level faster, such as equipping two shields, or attacking your own party members. All of which can be done fairly early in the game to gain a massive advantage that can trivialize much of the games content. There is also an optional dungeon at the end that brings back in the temporary party members for their own bonus adventure that was not in the original version of the game.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>gba</category><category>review</category><category>video game</category><guid>https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/posts/final-fantasy-originsff1-ff2/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 27 Mar 2021 03:48:32 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>