<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Model Human Processor (Posts about book reviews)</title><link>https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/categories/cat_book-reviews.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2021 &lt;a href="mailto:modelhumanprocessor@protonmail.com"&gt;Model Human Processor&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2021 03:12:51 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Roll Over and Die - I will fight for an ordinary life with my love and cursed sword vol 1</title><link>https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/posts/roll-over-and-die-i-will-fight-for-an-ordinary-life-with-my-love-and-cursed-sword-vol-1/</link><dc:creator>Model Human Processor</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;Classic Light Novel title giving you the basic premise for the story. And another entry in the 'kicked out of the hero party' sub-genre which seems to have developed a few tropes around it. Mainly that the character is viewed as useless but actually does serve some important function, or their abilities/special skills are considered weak or useless but are actually very strong.
This one dials up some that trope by not just kicking her out of the party, but selling her into slavery. There's a fair bit of gore that gets played up due to the Flum's healing ability once the sword mentioned in the title is acquired.
Mild yuri elements get sort of shoehorned in, but provide the heroine with some new purpose or direction to keep going with life instead of giving up. Other tropes include the ambiguity of the role of the demons the hero party is supposed to be fighting against versus the chruch that is backing the heroes. The end of the volume teases a lot here, so it really tries to hook the reader in to keep going to find out the details.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>light novel</category><category>review</category><guid>https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/posts/roll-over-and-die-i-will-fight-for-an-ordinary-life-with-my-love-and-cursed-sword-vol-1/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2021 03:06:49 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Kuma Kuma Kuma Bear vol 6</title><link>https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/posts/kuma-kuma-kuma-bear-vol-6/</link><dc:creator>Model Human Processor</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;Yuna fulfils her promise from the previous volume. Escorting some students in the capitol. Of course there's some extra trouble involved to keep things interesting. After her friend from the seaside town arrives and everyone is busy getting the new shop ready. Closing out sets up the events for the next volume in looking for a new knife for Fina. As always anyone new who disparages the bear gets a lesson in judging a book by its cover.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>light novel</category><category>review</category><guid>https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/posts/kuma-kuma-kuma-bear-vol-6/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 01:33:07 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>By the Grace of the Gods vol 4</title><link>https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/posts/by-the-grace-of-the-gods-vol-4/</link><dc:creator>Model Human Processor</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;The (mostly) slow life continues. Despite the continued interference of jealous rival tamers the business ventures of Ryoma continue to do well, so well that he is expanding into another town. There is some other developments with Ryoma starting to make preparations to raise his adventurer rank in order to claim the inheritance of his adopted grandparents. But that will have to be in later volumes. There were a few minor additions from the WN version in this volume, but nothing really of note.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>light novel</category><category>review</category><guid>https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/posts/by-the-grace-of-the-gods-vol-4/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jun 2021 19:26:01 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Trapped in a Dating Sim volume 2</title><link>https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/posts/trapped-in-a-dating-sim-volume-2/</link><dc:creator>Model Human Processor</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;Leon continues to cause trouble for himself with every choice he makes. He attempts to get the expected story of the game back on track after all his meddling, but that fails and he finds some resolve to take responsibility for how things have gone astray. Main events are the wrapping up of the school festival, followed by the school trip. Some new side characters are introduced, and some characters have a more favorable view of Leon by the end of this volume despite all the trouble he'd caused in volume 1.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>light novel</category><category>review</category><guid>https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/posts/trapped-in-a-dating-sim-volume-2/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 30 May 2021 05:40:33 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>By the Grace of the Gods</title><link>https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/posts/by-the-grace-of-the-gods/</link><dc:creator>Model Human Processor</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;A rather traditional 'isekai' story. The protagonist is an unfortunate office worker reincarnated with the skills acquired while he was alive plus some extra gifted skills like the requiset magic. In the first volume he reincarnates, proceeds to live a 'slow life' in the woods for awhile, until meeting a noble and his guards, then moving to the nearby town, becoming an adventurer, etc. The kind of standard fare you'd expect from a fantasy isekai.
Volume 2 continues the story where the protagonist takes a break from adventuring to work some side hustles alongside his adventure guild tasks.
Volume 3 has his side job in full swing, and ends with parting with the noble family that had been central to him coming into town in the first place. Which if I remember correctly from when I read the web novel version this more or less wraps up the first major arc.
It's a fairly solid slice of life isekai if that's what you're into. There's no grand quest for him to slay the demon lord or save the world. There is some side plots with a bit of intrigue here and there, and the standard way that reincarnators stir up various kinds of trouble and attention that keep the story moving along.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>light novel</category><category>review</category><guid>https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/posts/by-the-grace-of-the-gods/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 16 May 2021 05:14:42 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>How to Read a Book(the book)</title><link>https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/posts/how-to-read-a-bookthe-book/</link><dc:creator>Model Human Processor</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;At first glance the title seems like a chicken and egg problem, but it's not about the mechanical aspect of being able to read and understanding the words, it's about how to parse and select books to see if they might be 'worth' reading, or if you need to read several books on the same topic. I originally found out about this book when it came up as a recommendation for people pursuring graduate studies or researchers.
In some ways I feel the value of this particular book has diminished somewhat thanks to the internet, especially when looking for books at the beginner and intermediate level for any given topic. It's typically quite easy to search the web and find book lists or blog posts that suggest a solid set of books to start with for just about anything you can think of to search for. But if you are moving into advanced research, or looking for niche topics where such convienent lists may not exist or be hard to come by, that's when the ideas presented in this book come in handy.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>bookreview</category><guid>https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/posts/how-to-read-a-bookthe-book/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 16 May 2021 05:06:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Sorcerer King and Barbarian Queen vol 2</title><link>https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/posts/sorcerer-king-and-barbarian-queen-vol-2/</link><dc:creator>Model Human Processor</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;The adventure of our unreliable narrator continues. Having arrived in town our amnesiatic hero wastes no time in getting into some kind of new trouble. The protagonists inner monologue and his actions are frequently in conflict and this is a major source of humor for the this series.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>light novel</category><category>review</category><guid>https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/posts/sorcerer-king-and-barbarian-queen-vol-2/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2021 15:25:57 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Sorcerer King of Destruction and the Golem of the Barbarian Queen</title><link>https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/posts/the-sorcerer-king-of-destruction-and-the-golem-of-the-barbarian-queen/</link><dc:creator>Model Human Processor</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;Well with the general premise right in the title what more is there to say? Another isekai although given the character gets much of his memory erased and knowledge from his life makes basically zero impact on the events in this volume, it seems like the isekai setting is mostly just a convienent starting point for the story and lore rather than adhering more closely to the standard tropes. Which is a welcome change of pace, the main character has some idiosincraticies that perhaps didn't translate well or are a type of cultural meme that I'm just missing.
The story itself is an amusing read. Our hapless main character narrowly avoids his fate, and ends up creating a golem to be his partner. It's clear that his golem is a bit special and that gets hinted at throughout.
This first volume covers the main characters arrival, setting out from the starting location, some trials, and finally arriving in civilization.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>light novel</category><category>review</category><guid>https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/posts/the-sorcerer-king-of-destruction-and-the-golem-of-the-barbarian-queen/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 17 Apr 2021 04:38:12 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>