<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Model Human Processor (Posts about DS)</title><link>https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/categories/ds.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2021 &lt;a href="mailto:modelhumanprocessor@protonmail.com"&gt;Model Human Processor&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 18:19:28 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Super Mario 64 DS</title><link>https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/posts/super-mario-64-ds/</link><dc:creator>Model Human Processor</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;I never had the chance to own a Nintendo 64 console when they were current, so when I saw this remake/port for the DS I snapped it up, never having had a chance to fully play through the original N64 version. The DS version is pretty faithful although adds some new features and mini games, the controls could be a bit clunky at times, although I recall the N64 controls also having a few awkward moments but it still works and is very playable. This game is pretty classic as it marked the first shift from 2d platformers into 3d and set the stage for the Mario Galaxy games on the Wii, and Mario Obyssey on Switch. The only time the controls and particularly the camera controls frustrated me was during the final boss, although part of that is just me being bad at getting the timing of the throw correct. I only went for 80/150 stars, which many fans would consider sacriligious. But I'd rather move on to other games or save doing a full star run for the non-handheld version.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>DS</category><category>review</category><category>video game</category><guid>https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/posts/super-mario-64-ds/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 18:10:58 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Rhapsody A Musical Adventure</title><link>https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/posts/rhapsody-a-musical-adventure/</link><dc:creator>Model Human Processor</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;Although the original game was released for Playstation in July 2000 and was a tactical rpg, the DS remake in 2008 switches the combat to be a more standard turn based jrpg. Some content was also taken out from the post game. It is very much a beginner jrpg, with a hint of where to go next in the status screen so even if you take an extended break you won't be totally lost of where you left off. Not  that many breaks are needed, the game itself is fairly short even when you complete the side stories to recruit more puppets. Speaking the side stories, it is possible to miss out on some of them if you advance  the story too far before completeing the side quests which is always a disappointment for me. The story is cute and an inversion of the more standard fantasy rpg story. The combat system is decent enough if a little basic, and although there's a fairly high encounter rate you can enable auto battle to sweep through the low difficulty mobs and enter manual commnds for bosses or as needed.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>DS</category><category>review</category><category>video games</category><guid>https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/posts/rhapsody-a-musical-adventure/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 18:00:35 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>