<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Model Human Processor (Posts about light novel)</title><link>https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/categories/light-novel.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2021 &lt;a href="mailto:modelhumanprocessor@protonmail.com"&gt;Model Human Processor&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Apr 2021 04:48:09 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>The Sorcerer King of Destruction and the Golem of the Barbarian Queen</title><link>https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/posts/the-sorcerer-king-of-destruction-and-the-golem-of-the-barbarian-queen/</link><dc:creator>Model Human Processor</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;Well with the general premise right in the title what more is there to say? Another isekai although given the character gets much of his memory erased and knowledge from his life makes basically zero impact on the events in this volume, it seems like the isekai setting is mostly just a convienent starting point for the story and lore rather than adhering more closely to the standard tropes. Which is a welcome change of pace, the main character has some idiosincraticies that perhaps didn't translate well or are a type of cultural meme that I'm just missing.
The story itself is an amusing read. Our hapless main character narrowly avoids his fate, and ends up creating a golem to be his partner. It's clear that his golem is a bit special and that gets hinted at throughout.
This first volume covers the main characters arrival, setting out from the starting location, some trials, and finally arriving in civilization.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>light novel</category><category>review</category><guid>https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/posts/the-sorcerer-king-of-destruction-and-the-golem-of-the-barbarian-queen/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 17 Apr 2021 04:38:12 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Trapped in a Dating Sim: The world of otome games is tough for mobs</title><link>https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/posts/trapped-in-a-dating-sim-the-world-of-otome-games-is-tough-for-mobs/</link><dc:creator>Model Human Processor</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;The general premise is right there in the title. Our protagonist reincarnates into the world of game his sister had blackmailed him to play for her. Which is a reasonable explanation to have someone who would not be the target audience of such a game play through it. The description of the game from the prologue also allows the world to be nonsensical and inconsistent in various places due to it being based on a silly game and thus still fit the story.
The one part that doesn't really fit for me is the protagonists insistance on following through with the 'logic' of the otome game world when it comes to his position and what's expected of him with finding a marriage partner. He's perfectly willing and even hoping to throw away his title to avoid having to marry some harpy, but when that fails he goes right back into the mindset of having to find a wife. There is an explanation given, but considering Leon's ownership of Luxion he hardly has any reason to be concerned. Aside from that it's a rather enjoyable story overall. Leon just can't stay out of trouble.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>book review</category><category>light novel</category><guid>https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/posts/trapped-in-a-dating-sim-the-world-of-otome-games-is-tough-for-mobs/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2021 04:55:30 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>In Another World With My Smartphone(LN)</title><link>https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/posts/in-another-world-with-my-smartphoneln/</link><dc:creator>Model Human Processor</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;A fairly trope laden isekai LN. Protagonist is overpowered from the start? Check, can use all magic? check, early harem setup? check, harem includes royalty? check, picks a katana as weapon? check. There's no real surprises here folks.
The smartphone gimmick from the title is a handy McGuffin item. Allowing the protagonist to referrence the internet to look up things he doesn't know how to do, exploit it's mapping feature in conjunction with magic, look up new recipes to introduce new food items, all the standard things you often get when a protagonist is some kind of isekai prepper but instead is just a regular guy but still has access to google thanks to the smartphone cheat.
I can't remember exactly what volume they get foreshadowed around 3~4 iirc, but volume 6 introduces mechas. So if you miss the earlier foreshadowing like I did and end up invested in the story having this addition really throws a wrench in the more traditional fantasy setting I prefer and goes full mech otaku. A feature that will be present in one form or another in pretty much every subsequent volume that I've read (currently have read up to and including volume 12). I've honestly debated dropping this series but tend to fall for the sunk cost fallacy and feeling that I've come this far, I might as well just keep going. It's still a fun story if you enjoy isekai series.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>isekai</category><category>light novel</category><category>review</category><guid>https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/posts/in-another-world-with-my-smartphoneln/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 02 Apr 2021 17:02:51 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Kuma Kuma Kuma Bear</title><link>https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/posts/kuma-kuma-kuma-bear/</link><dc:creator>Model Human Processor</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cute girls doing cute things the isekai? When self proclaimed hermit Yuna opens a special event box in her VRMMORPG she ends up transported to a fantasy world with her event reward (a set of bear themed equipment) and a ton of money. The main hook of her equipment being the source of abilities meaning she can never get rid of it is still a source of amusement for me even after 5 volumes, the joke hasn't gotten old yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The various arcs are more or less what one might expect from a fantasy world isekai, adventurer and merchant guilds, nobles, fighting monsters, food, etc. the fact that the protagonist is a girl in a bear onesie gives it all a fresh coat of paint and helps keep the tone fairly light hearted.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>light novel</category><category>review</category><guid>https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/posts/kuma-kuma-kuma-bear/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 17:21:50 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>