<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Model Human Processor (Posts about mmorpg)</title><link>https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/categories/mmorpg.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2021 &lt;a href="mailto:modelhumanprocessor@protonmail.com"&gt;Model Human Processor&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2021 01:10:01 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Blade and Soul(Astromancer patch?)</title><link>https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/posts/blade-and-soulastromancer-patch/</link><dc:creator>Model Human Processor</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;I made a brief return to Blade and Soul after seeing that some new classes had been released and the story had progressed a bit since my last time playing this over a year prior. So I reinstalled to see what's changed. And the answer was, not much. The main quest rewards to catch a new player/character up to speed to begin the dungeon grind have been increased a bit, but at the same time, so much content in the game is being made redundant and retired. And it's not being retired well, much of it is sloppy, it was confusing as a returning player and I feel it would also be confusing for any new player. Which all added up to the feeling that the game was running on the fumes of whatever dedicated fanbase remained.
After catching up on the story and trying out the new classes I quit again. The story is pretty grim and dark as far as MMORPGs go. And I just can't be bothered to learn the dungeon or raid encounters with my reduced level of interest in playing this game long term. Many of the features that originally got me to try this game have been stripped away or streamlined. Which is good in some ways, they were complex and grindy, but a shame in others.
Maybe I'll see where this game is at in another few years if it's still around.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>mmorpg</category><category>pc</category><category>review</category><category>video game</category><guid>https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/posts/blade-and-soulastromancer-patch/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2021 01:02:32 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>