<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Model Human Processor (Posts about pc)</title><link>https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/categories/pc.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2021 &lt;a href="mailto:modelhumanprocessor@protonmail.com"&gt;Model Human Processor&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2021 01:23:44 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Honkai Impact 3rd</title><link>https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/posts/honkai-impact-3rd/</link><dc:creator>Model Human Processor</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;Another mobile game from the same studio as Genshin Impact. After starting Genshin I was curious about Mihoyo's other game. So I tried this out, it's another gacha waifu collector. The battle system is quite similar to Genshin's with swapping characters to use abilites, a type system, some enemies having shields, etc. Although most parts of the game were localized there were some that were not, leading the already confusing story to be even more confusing. The gameplay was pretty fun, but the confusing story eventually lost me completely and my interest in continuing waned. There were some good events during the time I did play though and the game was quite enjoyable. So it might be something I pick up again at some point.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>pc</category><category>review</category><category>video game</category><guid>https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/posts/honkai-impact-3rd/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2021 01:19:15 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Blade and Soul(Astromancer patch?)</title><link>https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/posts/blade-and-soulastromancer-patch/</link><dc:creator>Model Human Processor</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;I made a brief return to Blade and Soul after seeing that some new classes had been released and the story had progressed a bit since my last time playing this over a year prior. So I reinstalled to see what's changed. And the answer was, not much. The main quest rewards to catch a new player/character up to speed to begin the dungeon grind have been increased a bit, but at the same time, so much content in the game is being made redundant and retired. And it's not being retired well, much of it is sloppy, it was confusing as a returning player and I feel it would also be confusing for any new player. Which all added up to the feeling that the game was running on the fumes of whatever dedicated fanbase remained.
After catching up on the story and trying out the new classes I quit again. The story is pretty grim and dark as far as MMORPGs go. And I just can't be bothered to learn the dungeon or raid encounters with my reduced level of interest in playing this game long term. Many of the features that originally got me to try this game have been stripped away or streamlined. Which is good in some ways, they were complex and grindy, but a shame in others.
Maybe I'll see where this game is at in another few years if it's still around.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>mmorpg</category><category>pc</category><category>review</category><category>video game</category><guid>https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/posts/blade-and-soulastromancer-patch/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2021 01:02:32 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Genshin Impact</title><link>https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/posts/genshin-impact/</link><dc:creator>Model Human Processor</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;I was purely f2p during my time playing Genshin Impact. When I first started seeing comments about this crop up on social media one of the descriptions I came across was "Breath of the Waifu/Husbando" for it's open world gameplay and combat combined with a gacha system for monetization. So I tried it out for longer than I was intending to, completeing all the current story content and doing the daily grind of farming primogems to pull for characters. The open world is fun to explore, hunting for chests and solving the odd puzzle.
The game suffers from the same problem as others within the gacha/mobile genre, stamina limits, grinding, rather predetory monetization with paid stamina refreshes. That being said I never felt overly pressured to spend money, the natural resin(stamina) refresh was enough to do a few events each day, and the game gave out a reasonable about of resin potions that I saved up until hitting the appropriate rank to utilize them effectively.
The team building is pretty flexible although as always a lot of min maxing takes place to build up some kind of meta, and although conforming to the meta might help clear some of the hardest content sooner and with easier to acquire equipment, you can stray from the meta and still clear most of the content the game has to offer.
Once the story is cleared and the higher ranks are hit, the bulk of the game turns into grinding for artifacts/equipment. This is heavily RNG based and a massive source of frustration for many players especially if you're attempting to clear the harder challenge dungeon with a sub-optimal team comp, or even an optimal team comp if your gear RNG has been terrible.
After playing a few months I've had my fill, I'll likely check back in from time to time as new patches hit to keep up with the story and try some of the events. The tower defense mini game in the previous event was pretty fun. But the endless rng gear grind just really kills my motivation to play daily any more.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>pc</category><category>review</category><category>video game</category><guid>https://www.modelhumanprocessor.com/posts/genshin-impact/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2021 00:47:42 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>